Rayta Amin

Human Resources Coordinator

Shantibagh, Dhaka-1217 | +8801533787083 or +8801842646499 | rayta.amin@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/rayta-amin/

Summary

Highly adaptable and agile in collaboration and teamwork, effective in critical, conceptual and analytical thinker in any global or multicultural setting with four years of depth understanding of Human Resource Management and overall business process and One-year of Professional Certification on HRM (PGDHRM).

Core Competencies

- · Strategic Planning
- · Customer & Staff Relationship
- · Human Resource Planning
- · Labor Law
- · Human Resource Development
- Communication
- Resource Allocation
- Territory Management Research & Analysis
- Competitive Intelligence
- Team Leadership
- · Industrial Health & Safety
- Documentation
- Compensation and Benefits
- · Employee Motivation and Counseling



Professional Certification

Post Graduation Diploma in Human Resource Management (PGDHRM)

Program Description: The diploma course in Human Resource Management is designed to suit the requirements of labour and social welfare officers, personnel managers and similar officers/executives engaged in Human resource management/human resource management functions and those desirous to make a career in Human Resource Management

Awarding Body: Bangladesh Institute of Management (BIM)

Affiliated By: Ministry of Industries, Government of The People's Republic of Bangladesh.

Professional Experience

Human Resources Coordinator

December, 2019 - Present

Shadmart Bangladesh

Job Responsibilities:

- · Respond to internal and external HR related inquiries or requests and provide assistance
- · Redirect HR related calls or distribute correspondence to the appropriate person of the team
- · Maintain records of personnel-related data (payroll, personal information, leaves, turnover rates etc.) through HRIS software and ensure all employment requirements are met.
- · Liaise with other departments or functions (payroll, benefits etc.)
- · Support the recruitment/hiring process by sourcing candidates, performing background checks, assisting in shortlisting, issuing employment contracts etc.
- · Assist supervisors in performance management procedures.
- · Schedule meetings, interviews, HR events etc. and maintain the team's agenda.
- · Coordinate training sessions and seminars.
- · Perform orientations, onboarding and update records with new hires.
- · Ensures planning, monitoring, and appraisal of employee work results by training managers to coach and discipline employees; scheduling management conferences with employees;
- Ensure that HR policies and processes are effectively communicated to staff and also update staff on changes in HR policies
- · Assist in ad-hoc HR projects, i.e. collect employee feedback, etc.

Trainee Intern

11/09/2018 - 13/12/2018

IFIC BANK LIMITED

Job Responsibilities:

- · Maintain all administrative duties.
- · Maintain Petty Cash.
- · The local community activities to represent the bank.
- · Receiving the cheque, help the client by giving information about different loan schemes.
- · Help the client to open a bank account.
- · Transactional Management etc.

Achievements

- · Gained a certificate from the College for participating in Business Plan Exhibition.
- · Got Junior Scholarship (Talent pool).
- · Best Science project award and certificate from the college.
- · Champion in Quiz War (General Knowledge) in East West University TELCO WARFARE.
- INDEX Presents HR CALIBRATION 2.0 (Case Competition)
- · Bisshwa Shaitya Kendro Book Reading Competition (1st Prize)
- Recitation School Poetry Competition (1st Prize)

Technological Proficiencies

- · Microsoft Word (Advanced)
- Microsoft PowerPoint (Advanced)
- Microsoft Excel (Intermediate)
- Adobe Illustrator (Basic)
- Adobe Photoshop (Basic)

Communication & Analytical Skills

Communication Skills:

- · Skilled in all sorts of communicational correspondence.
- · Capable of conducting multimedia presentation.

Notable Academic Projects

- "Problem & Prevention of Overweight and Obesity: How Effective the Current Public Health Approach" (Genre: Public Health)
- "Poetry Reading and It's Importance to our life" (Genre: English Literature)
- HR Analysis of Different MNC's in Bangladesh (Coca-Cola, British American Tobacco Bangladesh, Standard Chartered Bank, Unilever Bangladesh, Hotel Radisson Blu, Airtel, Novartis, Marico etc.) (Genre: Human Resource Management).
- "An Analysis of General Banking Activities of IFIC BANK (Bangladesh)". (Genre: Academic Thesis)

Education

Bachelor of Business Administration in Human Resource Management 2014 - 2018

North South University, Dhaka-Bangladesh.

Major Courses:

- · Human Resource Planning
- · Managerial Skills Development
- · Compensation & Benefits
- Industrial Relations
- · Human Resource Management in Bangladesh
- Strategic Human Resource Management

CGPA: 2.60 out of 4.00

Higher Secondary Certificate (H.S.C)

2011 - 2013

Viqarunnisa Noon College, Dhaka-Bangladesh.

Group: Business Studies

GPA: 5.00 out of 5.00

Secondary School Certificate (S.S.C),

Vigarunnisa Noon School, Dhaka-Bangladesh.

Group: Business Studies

GPA: 4.88 out of 5.00

Additional Information

- Date of Birth: 07-10-1996
- Religion: Muslim
- · Blood Group: O+
- · Father's Name: Khairul Amin
- Mother's Name: Khaleda Amin
- · Hometown: Chandpur
- Hobbies: I love to read books, Listening Classical Music, K-Pop, Rock Music, Handicrafts, Painting, Poetry Recitation, Watching Korean & Chinese Dramas and Travelling.

Extra-Curricular Activities

- General Member, North South University Shangskritik Sangathan (NSUSS) (2015-2017)
- General Member, North South University HR Club (2016-2018)
- Senior Executive (Vigarunnisa Noon Debating Club) (2013-2016)
- Program Coordinator (Vigarunnisa Noon School Language Club) (2011-2014)
- Treasurer (Vigarunnisa Noon School Science Club) (2011-2012)

- Efficient in documentation and writing reports.
- Have initiative, take self-motivation and can work independently or as part of a team
- Can work with people of all levels and motivate them to get things done.
- Capable in handling workload under any situation to achieve deadlines.

Analytical Skills:

 Being able to effectively research and gather data.

- · Can solve problem quickly.
- · Try to think logically.

Area of Interest

- Human Resource Management
- Human Resource Development
- · Core Administration
- · Market Research
- Documentation
- Talent Acquisition
- Training & Development
- · Industrial Health & Safety
- Labor Law
- Business Development
- · Labor Welfare
- Research & Publications

References

Mohammed Rashed Uzzaman

Lecturer

Department of Management

School of Business & Economics

North South University

Plot#15, Block-B, Bashundhara, Dhaka-1212, Bangladesh.

Contact No: +8801683819392

F-mail

rashed.uzzaman@northsouthedu.com

James Rollense Sarker

Transaction Service Manager

IFIC BANK LIMITED

24, Shantinagar, Dhaka-1217, Bangladesh.

Contact No: +8801930383722

E-mail: james.rollense@ificbankbd.com